Rogvi David Arge

Data Science & Optimization Consultant

 $+45\ 5042\ 5002$

argeinnovations@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/rogvidarge/en

github.com/rogvid

SUMMARY

Data Scientist with more than 4 years of experience in agile project development and a passion for deep learning, predictive analytics and optimization. Vast experience in data wrangling, exploratory data analysis, machine learning and data visualization and applying these skills to generate corporate wide improvements.

EXPERIENCE

Owner | Arge Innovations

Dec. 2018 - Present

Agile development and deployment of data science, machine learning, and optimization products.

Data Science Consultant | DFDS A/S | Dec. 2018 - May 2019 Spearheaded a paradigmshift of the transportation & logistics industry by:

- Helping reduce RMSE of prediction algorithm by 20% and implementing a number of scalable machine learning model
- Enabling a completely new transportation planning paradigm by implementing optimization tool that visualized plans to users

Data Scientist | ATP

Feb. 2017 - Dec. 2018

Matured the data science efforts within social benefit fraud detection

- Reduced prediction failures caused by server downtime by building a Flask based server/database monitoring system
- Enabled investigation of people with complex fraud patterns by implementing a hybrid machine learning expert system model
- Reduced payments of social benefits to fraudulent people by more than 10 mio. using expert systems

Data Analyst | ConWX

Apr. 2015 - Feb. 2017

Used analytics and machine learning to increase client revenue and implemented software solutions to distribute these models to customers

- \bullet Greatly increased one of our largest clients monthly revenue by discovering a way to improve our forecasts by 18%
- Designed and developed a monitoring system essential for forecast quality assurance and improvement

EDUCATION

M.Sc. in Physics | University of Copenhagen 2012 - 2015

Focus on computational physics, machine learning and mathematical modeling.

B.Sc. in Physics | University of Copenhagen Focus on laser physics, optics, and quantum mechanics.

2009 - 2012

CERTIFICATIONS

Deep Learning Specialization | Coursera

2017 - 2018

Development of deep learning models in Tensorflow & Keras. Specialization taught by Andrew Ng on Coursera.

Data Analyst Nanodegree | Udacity

2015 - 2017

Project based courses teaching essential knowledge and skills for data scientists.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python	••••
Machine Learning	••••
Optimization	••••
OR	••••
Data Visualization	••••
Data Analysis	••••
Modeling	••••
Statistics	••••
Git	••••
SQL	••••
Deep Learning	••••
Flask	••••
API	••••
D3	••••
HTML	••••
CSS	••••
JavaScript	••••
C#	••••
Docker	••••
AWS	••••
Azure	••••
MongoDB	••••
R	••••

SOFT SKILLS

Problem Solving	••••
Critical Thinking	••••
Communication	••••
Adaptability	••••
Project Planning	••••
Decision Making	••••
Scrum	••••

LANGUAGES

Faroese	••••
Danish	••••
English	••••
Norwegian	••••
Swedish	••••
French	••••